Cuong Pham

☑ cuongquocpham151@gmail.com | in cuongpham281 | ♀ cqpham28 | ❖ https://cqpham28.github.io

PROFESSIONAL INTERESTS

I have a strong interest in data-driven techniques incorporating signal processing and machine learning methods for healthcare research with the goal of enhancing the digitalization of the computer-aid medical system. I conduct human-based biosignal experiments and analyze multi-modal biomedical datasets associated to different sub-domain studies in neurology, cardiology, and digital remote monitoring.

EDUCATION

Ritsumeikan University

Shiga, Japan

M.Eng. in Advanced Information Science and Engineering

2021 - 2023

- Fully-funded MEXT Scholar
- Relevant Courses: Adv. Topics in Global Software Engineering, Adv. Topics in Communication Science, Adv. Topics in Human Factors for System Engineering, Adv. Topics for Knowledge-based System.
- Remarks: GAKKAI Scholarship | GPA: 3.6/5.0

VNU-HCM University of Technology

HCMC, Vietnam

2015 - 2020

B.Eng. in Physics Engineering

- Biomedical Engineering Specialization
- Relevant Courses: Numerical Methods, Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Digital Signal Processing, Medical Instrumentation and Labs, Sensors and Measurement Techniques
- Remarks: 1st-rank Faculty Honors (2016) | major-GPA: 8.13/10

WORK EXPERIENCE

VinUni-Illinois Smart Health Center, VinUniversity

Hanoi, Vietnam

CS PhD Candidate (Advisor: Dr. Hieu Pham, Dr. Huong Ha)

Aug 2024 - now

- Mental Health Research
 - * Research Coordinator: project management for a team of 10 multidisciplinary experts and students; working with hospitals/clinics for a large-scale digital-phenotying Vietnamese cohorts.
 - * Software Development: building and maintaining project website for streamlined content; designing and developing a full-stack Android/IOS mobile app for user configuration;
 - * Data Collection System: developing admin dashboard allowing the integration of wearable devices and smartphones for seamless multimodal data acquisition; setup Cloud-based secured storage and synchronization.
- Multimodal AI Research
 - * Conducted literature review on (1) mental health and neurological diseases; (2) benchmark multimodal frameworks.
 - * Testing new modeling frameworks on digital phenotyping studies and comparing to its replicated baseline.

School of Biomedical Engineering, VNU-HCM International University

HCMC, Vietnam

Research Assistant (Advisor: Dr. Huong Ha)

Nov 2023 - Jul 2024

- Brain Computer Interface (BCI) Research: involved in experimental protocol design and calibration with PsychoPy x EEG data acquisition & management tasks; conducted literature review and wrote technical documentation; conducted tutorial seminars of signal processing to students.
- Tech-lead BCI Modeling: serialized and processed the collected in-house datasets; developed ML pipeline for predictive modeling tasks; conducted performance benchmarking with other data sources; deployed and maintained web apps for Cloud storage, performance response analysis and data visualization.
- Online-BCI: collaborated with the software developers to build a customized desktop app for BCI data acquisition and response controller; deployed and evaluated user-specific calibrated modeling for real-time mouse control system; conducted inspection process to integrate the platform into a project by KC4.0-MOST.

HATO Medical Technologies ApS

Machine Learning Engineer

Odense, Denmark Jun 2022 – Nov 2023

• Cardiology Research: worked closely with cardiologists and health-tech startup stakeholders to establish standardized clinical labeling protocols tailored to specific use cases at a local Danish emergency department focusing on final outcomes for cardiovascular diseases; conducted literature reviews for evidence-based decision making, wrote technical documentation, prepared research materials and wrote grant proposals/fundings.

- Data Pipeline: collected and handled data from public repositories and clinical sources. Implemented a scalable data processing pipeline, including data cleaning, and alignment across sources. Collaborated with software developers to integrate a data serialization pipeline into the backend architecture of the in-house product.
- AI/ML Development: implemented a cloud-based internal data management system with interactive web app and tested its streamline workflow. Monitored and evaluated time-series predictive modeling; deployed models for real-time abnormalities detection and interpretation; inspected and ensured the solution meet technical requirements.

GSISE, Ritsumeikan University

Shiga, Japan

M.Eng Research Assitant (Advisor: Dr. Koji Kashihara)

Oct 2021 - Aug 2023

- Drug Infusion Research: developed a hybrid controller to regulate cardiac output and mean arterial pressure within during drug infusion using ML model with short-time previous drug inputs; evaluated on a mathematical modeling responses of dogs with heart-failure dataset.
- RPPG Signal Quality Enhancement: designed pipeline to track landmarks on customized forehead region-of-interest, using combination of unsupervised optical models and deep auto-encoder network to improve signal-to-noise ratio; evaluated on public remote-photoplethysmograph datasets.
- RPPG Constrainst-based Experiments: collected data (5 healthy subjects with different camera settings & postures); designed platform to synchronize facial video and blood volume pulse signal; evaluated heart rate benchmarks among different configurations with unsupervised methods and statistical analysis.
- RPPG Feature Waveform Assessment: investigated the reliability of waveform feature related to cardiac aging/stiffness by using a real-time Face-Mesh tracking with deep learning model and a customized morphology extraction; evaluated on a public well controlled rPPG dataset.

GTOPIA Vietnam. Ltd

HCMC, Vietnam

Signal Processing Intern (Advisor: Dr. Liem Huynh)

Jan - Jun 2020

- Wearable Research: designed pipeline with API for raw data aggregation from in-house wearable product; designed signal processing pipeline for vital-sign hemodynamic monitoring; conducted experiments on commercial wristbands's performance under different usage scenarios.
- Data Collection: collaborated with Ho-Chi-Minh-Heart-Institute for large-scale clinical data acquisition. Processed, categorized, and digitalized health records of administered patients with cardiovascular diseases.

Biomedical Electronics Laboratory, Shibaura Institute of Technology

Tokyo, Japan

Research Intern (Advisor: Dr. Shinichiro Kanoh)

Sep - Nov 2019

• EEG Experimental Research: involved in data collection activities for Auditory and Motor Imagery studies; conducted experimental analysis on EEG visualization for motor cortex response and how to conduct neuro-feedback. Revised experiment procedure for the Bachelor Thesis.

PUBLICATION

Peer-reviewed Conference Paper

- C. Pham and K. Kashihara (2022, March), A Hybrid Controller for Multiple Drug Infusion in Heart Failure using Convolutional Neural Network. In 2022 IEEE 4th Global Conference on Life Sciences and Technologies (LifeTech) (pp. 340-344). [paper] [github]
- Nguyen, M. T. D., **Pham, C. Q.**, Nguyen, H. N., Le, K. Q., & Huynh, L. Q. (2022), A Statistical Approach to Evaluate Beta Response in Motor Imagery-Based Brain-Computer Interface. *In 8th International Conference on the Development of Biomedical Engineering in Vietnam (pp. 203-217)*. [paper] [github]

Thesis

• Cuong Pham, Remote Photoplethysmography Assessment Using Deep Learning (2023, Aug), Master Thesis @ Graduate School of Information Science and Engineering, Ritsumeikan University.

ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

Teaching Assistant

- [Fall 2024] Computer Vision @ CECS, VinUniversity. Prepared materials, instructed and evaluated student programming practice lab sessions on computer vision topics.
- [Fall 2022] Experiments in Artificial and Natural Intelligence @ CISE, Ritsumeikan University. Instructed students to conduct biosensors experiments, calibrated and maintained lab's equipments/softwares.

University Projects

- [Sep 2022 Jan 2023] WasteWise @ GSISE, Ritsumeikan University (Japan). Team of 6 collaborate with TH Nürnberg (Germany) on a ML-based mobile app for trash bins time collection recommendation in public spaces using crowdsourcing data; evaluated on a pilot self-collected data in Shiga, Japan. [notes]
- [Sep 2018 Mar 2019] Stationary Bike @ VNU-HCM University of Technology (Vietnam). Designed circuits for workload adjustment adapting to the biker's heart rate. Collaborated with HCMC Institute of Biomedical Physics for endurance course design; evaluated VO2max improvement on students. [notes]
- [Mar Jul 2017] Pet Feeder @ VNU-HCM University of Technology (Vietnam). Tech-lead freelance team to design the low-cost automated pet-feeding system; conducted mechanical design and material 3D-printing, developed electrical circuits and platform for IoT user control; delivered to reserved clients. [notes]

Talks

- [Jun 2024] Poster Presentation @ NeuroCoB 2024 (Putrajaya, Malaysia). Evaluation of Cue-based Protocol Implementations in Motor Imagery based Brain-Computer Interface Experiments. [github]
- [Oct 2019] Poster Presentation @ <u>ISAS 2019</u> (HCMC, Vietnam). Exercise Physiology: Improving Stationary Bike Training Performance Using Heart Rate Variability.
- [Oct 2019] Project Presentation @ <u>iCAEP 6</u> (Thai Nguyen, Vietnam). Research into the relationship between cardiac responses and neural activity to improve classification of EEG-based imaginary action.
- [Mar 2019] Poster Presentation @ <u>SEATUC 2019</u> (Hanoi, Vietnam). Exercise Physiology: Cardiac Endurance Training for Students by Stationary Bike.

Community Involvement

- [Jan 2023] Teaching Assistant @ Ritsumeikan Junior High (Japan). Organized activities and trained language skills for Japanese junior students to join on-stage competition.
- [Oct 2022] Technical Staff @ IEEE/RSJ IROS 2022 (Japan). Managed attendees logistics; information desk; set up PC at venue; in charge of Webinar operations and supported technical issues.
- [Sep 2020 Apr 2021] EEG Study Group @ VNU-HCM University of Technology (Vietnam). Hosted a weekly knowledge sharing session among lab members concerning technical issues and practical tips in Polysomnography sleep studies; conducted tutorials on EEG analysis with MATLAB for students.

Mentoring Students

- Tuong Nguyen H., now Research Staff @ VNU-HCM International University (Vietnam).
- Hidetake Kondo, now Software Developer @ e-Jan Networks Co. (Japan).
- Ha Nguyen L. N., now Biomedical Engineer @ Cho Ray Hospital (Vietnam).

AWARDS

- [Aug 2022] 2nd prize in Kyoto Startup Weekend Competition; by Techstars x KYOTO Design Lab.
- [Sep 2021] Monbukagakusho Scholarship; by Japanese Government.

SELECTED SKILLS

- Programming: Python, MATLAB, Linux, R, SQL, Javascript, C#
- Machine Learning: OpenCV, Scikit-learn, LightGBM, XGBoost, Keras, Pytorch, Lightning
- Tech Stacks: Database (MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase), Webapp (Streamlit, Flask), Mobile (React Native), Cloud AWS (S3, EC2, Lambda), Tools (Git, Docker, Jira)
- Miscellaneous: Data Analysis (scipy, pandas, ggplot2, dplyr), Bio-Signal Experimentation (ECG, EEG, PPG, wearable/bio-sensors), Signal Processing (spectral & time-frequency analysis, transformation [SVD, PCA, ICA], filtering IIR/FIR), Circuit (ESP32, Arduino, Raspberry Pi, IoT sensors)
- Language: Vietnamese (native), English (fluent)

REFERENCE

Hieu Pham, Ph.D.

Assistant Professor, College of Engineering & Computer Science (CECS) & Scientific Director, Entrepreneurship Lab (E-lab),

PI at VinUni-Illinois Smart Health Center, VinUniversity.

Email: hieu.ph@vinuni.edu.vn

Ha Thi Thanh Huong, Ph.D.

Head of Brain Health Lab &

Chair, Department of Tissue Engineering and Regenerative Medicine

School of Biomedical Engineering, International University

Vietnam National University in Ho Chi Minh city.

Email: htthuong@hcmiu.edu.vn

Stefan K. Johansen

COO, HATO Medical Technologies,

Partners & Board Members, Black Capital Ventures.

Email: skj@hatomedicaltechnologies.com